# Ing. Martin Kožený

Phone: (+420) 724 735 822

Email: martin.kozeny@gmail.com

#### Personal

Born on December 21, 1986.

Czech Republic Citizen.

Marital status: single.

Driving licence: yes (B).

Spoken languages: Czech - mothertongue, English - fluent, German - good, French - basic.

### **Profile**

I have quite a lot experiences with programming in Java (both J2SE and J2EE) and also interested in other programming languages and using alternative programming techniques. I passed during my studies many courses related to artifical intelligence which is also object of my interest. In my current work I deal with J2EE technologies and databases.

#### Education

Ing. Computer science - software engineering, Czech Technical University in Prague, 2009–2012.

International exchange student of computer science, University of New Orleans, 2011.

CISCO Networks certificate, CCNAE 1, 2010.

Bc. Computer science, Czech Technical University in Prague, 2006–2009.

First Certificate in English (FCE), 2006.

Grammar school Dašická Pardubice, 1998–2006.

## **Employment**

Software developer at Ample cz s.r.o. 2007–present.

*Duties*: Working on enteprise applications for government and for private sector involving its designing, modeling and implementation. Experiences with databases including data gathering and data normalizing for datawarehouse.

Tourist guide at Kinský dal Borgo, a.s. 2004–2011.

Duties: Tourist guide at castle Kost in summer season.

Ing. Martin Kožený

**Databases** 

## Areas of expertise

Programming languages

Java (J2SE, J2EE) SQL language C/C++ MS SQL Server

Smalltalk MS SQL Server Analysis

Ruby Mondrian

Lisp PostgreSQL Server

Prolog Oracle and also its PL/SQL extension

Haskell MySQL

*Tools* Administration

Eclipse Administration of Gnu/Linux

NetBeans MS Windows

\_\_\_\_ Application server Tomcat

ETL graphs
Visual Studio
JBoss

Enterprise Architect, Astah Apache

Enterprise Producedy Fishari

Web Development

CVS, SVN, Git

Ant

JBoss Seam framework Hibernate Jakarta Struts

Ajax UML 2.0 PHP

CSS Web Services

HTML Testing

XHTML Javascript DocBook

XML JQuery